so hi my name is Joe brewer and I'm a
change strategist continuing to develop
the knowledge content that culture
designers will need to be able to
intentionally create changes in
large-scale culture and large-scale
social systems I want to review another
book that was really helpful for me and
that is this one made to stick why some
ideas survive and others die by Chip and
dan heath now made the stick is kind of
like the the user centered design
approach to communication because what
this book does is it breaks down for you
how ideas will spread from one person to
another and what the psychological
properties are of those ideas you know
what makes an idea sticky and and why
those ideas are so difficult to get rid
of once they're out in a society so the
approach that's taken by the authors
chip in Dan they're both brothers one of
them focuses his career and his research
on the best teaching practices in
schools so he's traveled around the
world and looked at the best teachers
the best pedagogy the best learning
approaches and found out what really
works to get ideas to spread and stick
in an educational context now the other
studies urban legends and how how fake
stories or stories that are not true can
arise within a social context and then
spread around and be really difficult to
get rid of so you've probably heard the
story of the person who goes to the bar
has someone slip a drug into their drink
and then they wake up in a bathtub in a
cheap motel with you know packed and ice
with their kidneys removed or some
stories similar to that we've all heard
stories like this many of us have told
stories like this and the question that
this book answers is what is it about
those stories that makes them so sticky
so one thing that I really love about
made to stick is that it breaks down for
you what the features are of ideas so
what makes them memorable what makes
them emotionally engaging what makes
them novel and unique and interesting
what makes them socially relevant and
able to share you know all of these are
things that culture designers will need
to know if we want to spread ideas so if
you work in marketing or communications
public relations or just some grassroots
community group that's trying to get
your idea out there to stick in other
people's minds and to spread and shape
the conversation then you're definitely
going to want to read made to stick by
chick and dan heath it's one of the more
readable books it's very accessible it's
lively and fun full of lots of great
examples and more importantly it gives
you the practical guidelines for how to
create ideas that survive and thrive an
absolutely essential thing for cultural
designers so I hope that you go and get
your copy of made to stick today read it
learn from it and help spread ideas that
make the world a better place